ISAIAH LEACH

SUMMARY

Proven Software Development Engineer with over two years of experience with a specialization in C#, Javascript, React, Unit Testing, and Responsive Design. To demonstrate my ability to create, maintain, repair, and improve responsive, dynamic, and accessible websites, I designed and developed my react web application that interacts with the backend and database to provide a clean and easy-to-use consumer coffee distribution website. As a dedicated lifelong learner, I attended a 500+ hour coding Bootcamp where I learned industry best practices and design architecture using HTML, CSS3, JavaScript, Node.JS, Express, React, Redux, SQL, and Postgres. After my studies I joined a non-profit organization as a Frontend Engineer where I volunteered my skills and gained experience. Recently, I became part of Launch Consulting Group as a Software Development Engineer where I gained skills in C#, Azure Technologies and Test Driven Development.

SKILLS

- Languages: C#, Javascript, Typescript, SQL, NoSQL, HTML, CSS, Python, Java, JSON
- Libraries: React, Redux, Bcrypt, .NET, Pug
- Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, CosmosDB, SQL Server
- Testing: Mocha, Chai, NUnit, Jest, Selenium
- CI/CD: Azure, Azure DevOps, GIT, Heroku
- Other: Express.js, NodeJS, JWTs, Linux

In a developer role at your company I will...

- Code with clear communication, following company style guides.
- Write fully automated code tests in adherence to best practices.
- Leverage the current CICD pipeline in place or build new CICD pipelines from the ground up.
- Build responsive frontend designs to spec per the UX design.
- Build out API routes per RESTful design structure.
- Be supportive and accepting of constructive criticism.

EXPERIENCE

Launch Consulting Group - Software Development Engineer

Remote Dec 2022 - Present

- Created a proof of concept application that analyzes atmospheric data in an ASP.NET and Azure Functions backend that stores data in CosmosDB. Data served to the React frontend utilizes JavaScript libraries to chart and display the data on a historical timeline.
- Developed on a team working for a Fortune 500 tech company on an internal application using Azure and Azure DevOps to expand and refine features while communicating progress and ideas with our stakeholder.
- Collaborated on a 20+ person team to continue development on the React frontend of a large scale production application for a large construction company with over 1,800 employees.

Clearviction - Software Developer

Remote Oct 2022 - March 2023

- Implemented new features and developed solutions to existing issues within our React web application.
- Contributed to an Agile team environment to perform asynchronous work while maintaining clear communication and expectations using Kanban boards.
- Clarified our dev needs to non-technical team members and ensured consistent expectations between teams and disciplines.

PROJECTS

Petrichor Coffee

Remote Mar 2022 - Present

Designed React web application that interacts with the backend and database to provide a clean and easy-to-use consumer coffee distribution website. Single-page web application built to display a working knowledge of React, NodeJS, PostgreSQL, ExpressJS, Authentication/Authorization, and RESTful design.

- Constructed REST API, implementing SQL queries to validate/return data from the database.
- Designed a fast and responsive UI/UX to navigate with load times under 2 seconds on desktop devices.
- Addressed authentication and security concerns with JsonWebTokens, and the Bcrypt library.
- Deployed to the cloud to support a CI/CD pipeline using Render.

EDUCATION

Codecademy - Full Stack Engineering | Front End Engineering

Remote Mar 2020 - Sep 2021

Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards focused on HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, and Redux on the front-end, NodeJS, ExpressJS, SQL, Postgres, algorithms, and data structures on the back-end. Created and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks. Developed organized projects to support and implement my knowledge to exceed requirements without overengineering, following the KISS design principle.